export const GEOGRAPHYA2007 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The scale of the map as expressed in ratio form is",
A: "1:50,000",
B: "1:100,000",
C: "1:150,000",
D: "1:200,000",
answer: "D. 1:200,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The distance along the main road from Fura to Anum is approximately",
A: "19km",
B: "22 km",
C: "24 km",
D: "28km",
answer: "C. 24 km",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A left bank tributary of River Kia is River",
A: "Pan",
B: "Obi",
C: "Buba",
D: "Iju",
answer: "B. Obi",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The total area covered by the map is approximately",
A: "720 km2",
B: "840 km2",
C: "9602 km2",
D: "1000 km2",
answer: "B. 840 km2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The main occupation of the people of the area is",
A: "Trading.",
B: "Mining.",
C: "Farming.",
D: "Fishing.",
answer: "B. Mining.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The feature marked ▲ 568 is a",
A: "Survey beacon.",
B: "Trigonometrical station.",
C: "Benchmarkark.",
D: "Spot height",
answer: "B. Trigonometrical station.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. ANUNAM DISTRICT is located in a",
A: "Savanna belt.",
B: "Swamp forest belt.",
C: "Forest belt.",
D: "Sudan belt.",
answer: "B. Swamp forest belt.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The feature marked A-B can be described as a",
A: "Ridge.",
B: "Spur.",
C: "Col.",
D: "Pass.",
answer: "B. Spur.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following settlements is not visible from Funi?",
A: "Kaku",
B: "Babo",
C: "Kon",
D: "Basi",
answer: "B. Babo",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The distance as the crow flies from Fon to Basi is approximately",
A: "20km.",
B: "30 km.",
C: "35 km.",
D: "40 km.",
answer: "B. 30 km.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The average revenue from minerals for the year is",
A: "30 million dollars.",
B: "40 million dollars.",
C: "50 million dollars.",
D: "60 million dollars.",
answer: "C. 50 million dollars.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The total revenue accruing from crude oil for that year is",
A: "64 million dollars.",
B: "74 million dollars.",
C: "80 million dollars.",
D: "92 million dollars.",
answer: "D. 92 million dollars.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. By how much is the revenue from copper more than that of columbite for that year?",
A: "50 million dollars.",
B: "48 million dollars.",
C: "45 million dollars.",
D: "114 million dollars.",
answer: "A. 50 million dollars.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. What is the revenue generated from gold and diamond for that year?",
A: "80 million dollars.",
B: "94 million dollars.",
C: "100 million dollars.",
D: "35 million dollars.",
answer: "B. 94 million dollars.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Pie charts are best used for showing",
A: "Isobars.",
B: "Isohalines.",
C: "Isonephs.",
D: "lsohyets.",
answer: "A. Isobars.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The innermost part of the earth’s crust is the",
A: "Barysphere",
B: "Mesosphere.",
C: "Lithosphere.",
D: "Duricrust.",
answer: "A. Barysphere",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The circular horizon is used to prove the sphericity of the earth because the horizon as seen by the observer becomes",
A: "Compact with increasing height.",
B: "Flat with increasing height.",
C: "Wider with decreasing altitude.",
D: "Circular with decreasing altitude.",
answer: "D. Circular with decreasing altitude.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. What is the approximate distance between two places located 150N and 20 N on the same meridian?",
A: "500 km",
B: "555 km",
C: "620 km",
D: "680 km",
answer: "B. 555 km",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The chemical composition of the earth’s core is",
A: "Alumina and magnesia.",
B: "Iron and nickel.",
C: "Iron and silica.",
D: "Nickel and alumina.",
answer: "B. Iron and nickel.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The months in which the solstice occur are",
A: "June and December.",
B: "March and July.",
C: "January and July.",
D: "April and November.",
answer: "A. June and December.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following mountains in Africa resulted from folding?",
A: "Ruwenzori",
B: "Kenya",
C: "Cameroun",
D: "atlas",
answer: "D. atlas",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The instrument for measuring wind direction is the",
A: "Anemometer.",
B: "Barometer.",
C: "Hygrometer.",
D: "Wind vane.",
answer: "D. Wind vane.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following is not a form of precipitation?",
A: "Rainfall",
B: "Thunderstorm",
C: "Hail",
D: "sleet",
answer: "B. Thunderstorm",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The main source of energy in the atmosphere is",
A: "petroleum.",
B: "Coal.",
C: "The sun",
D: "Uranium.",
answer: "C. The sun",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Variations in the salinity of the oceans is represented on maps with",
A: "Isobars.",
B: "Isohalines.",
C: "Isonephs.",
D: "Isohyets.",
answer: "B. Isohalines.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The cheapest source of power for a large industry is",
A: "Water.",
B: "Petroleum.",
C: "Coal.",
D: "Gas.",
answer: "A. Water.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The major continental fishing grounds are bund",
A: "In the Tropical areas,",
B: "In the continental shelves where warm and cold currents meet.",
C: "Only in the cold waters.",
D: "Only off the eastern shores of the continents.",
answer: "B. In the continental shelves where warm and cold currents meet.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A well will always contain water if",
A: "It is sunk at the bottom of a hill.",
B: "It is sunk into sedimentary rocks.",
C: "Bottom of the well is far below the water table.",
D: "It is located in high rainfall region.",
answer: "C. Bottom of the well is far below the water table.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. “Trees are evergreen, with little or no undergrowth, liana epiphytes are common”. Which vegetation type is being described?",
A: "Desert.",
B: "Savannas.",
C: "Rainforest.",
D: "Tundra.",
answer: "B. Savannas.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following is a feature of river capture?",
A: "Watershed.",
B: "Wind gap.",
C: "Waterfall.",
D: "Ox-bow Lake.",
answer: "B. Wind gap.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The Richter Scale is used to measure the intensity of",
A: "Wind.",
B: "Sunshine.",
C: "Earthquake.",
D: "Lava flow.",
answer: "C. Earthquake.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Exfoliation occurs when rocks are subjected to",
A: "Sudden release of pressure from fault.",
B: "Alternate heating and cooling of surface rocks.",
C: "Frost action.",
D: "Excessive rainstorm in the semi-desert region.",
answer: "B. Alternate heating and cooling of surface rocks.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Uniform high temperatures and heavy rainfall distributed throughout the year are characteristics of the",
A: "Tropical Monsoon climate.",
B: "Sudan climate.",
C: "Equatorial climate.",
D: "Mediterranean climate.",
answer: "C. Equatorial climate.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following does not explain why Hot deserts have high temperatures?",
A: "Presence of clear cloudless sky.",
B: "Presence of dry air.",
C: "Ascending air.",
D: "Intense insolation.",
answer: "C. Ascending air.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Hydrological cycle involves",
A: "Constant water circulation between the and atmosphere.",
B: "Moisture exchange between land and sea.",
C: "Evaporation of water from land and sea.",
D: "Discharge of water from the atmosphere into the sea.",
answer: "A. Constant water circulation between the and atmosphere.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The amount of water vapour in the atmosphere which varies from place to place at different times of the day is referred to as",
A: "Hygrometer.",
B: "Saturation.",
C: "Dew-point.",
D: "Humidity.",
answer: "D. Humidity.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The polar climate can be found in",
A: "Southern USA.",
B: "Southern Australia.",
C: "Northern Canada.",
D: "Southern Russia.",
answer: "C. Northern Canada.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following is found in the lower course of a river?",
A: "Delta",
B: "Waterfall",
C: "Ravine",
D: "Gorge",
answer: "A. Delta",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Our physical environment consists of",
A: "Climate, soil, drainage and vegetation.",
B: "Soil, drainage, vegetation and water.",
C: "Soil, drainage, grassland and ocean.",
D: "Climate, soil, drainage, vegetation and other non-living substances.",
answer: "D. Climate, soil, drainage, vegetation and other non-living substances.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following is an environment friendly source of energy?",
A: "Fuel wood.",
B: "Gas.",
C: "Wind.",
D: "Petroleum.",
answer: "C. Wind.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following is not a condition for the formation of an artesian basin?",
A: "Rocks are synclinal in form.",
B: "Presence of a layer of permeable rock between layers of impermeable rock.",
C: "A layer of impermeable rock covers completely the surface of permeable rock.",
D: "Availability of copious rainfall to give supply of ground water.",
answer: "C. A layer of impermeable rock covers completely the surface of permeable rock.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following is an example of a slow type of mass movement?",
A: "rockfall",
B: "landslide",
C: "rockslide",
D: "talus creep",
answer: "D. talus creep",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The horizontal gully-like grooves carved out in a limestone pavement are called",
A: "Grykes.",
B: "Clints.",
C: "Dolines.",
D: "Swallow holes.",
answer: "B. Clints.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Plants are referred to as autotrophs because they",
A: "Are planted by man.",
B: "Provide food for mammals.",
C: "Are capable of regeneration.",
D: "Are self-nourishing organisms.",
answer: "D. Are self-nourishing organisms.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Man is the most dominant factor in the ecosystem because he",
A: "Is in the top echelon of creation.",
B: "Has acquired culture and possess technology to modify the natural environment.",
C: "Has little control over the living and non-living things of the environment.",
D: "Has a large brain and is capable of destroying the ecosystem.",
answer: "B. Has acquired culture and possess technology to modify the natural environment.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following is not a problem facing transport development in Africa?",
A: "Swampy terrain.",
B: "Inadequate capital",
C: "Poor planning",
D: "Climate variation",
answer: "A. Swampy terrain.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. One advantage of road transport over other modes of transportation is its",
A: "Affordability",
B: "Flexibility.",
C: "Punctual.",
D: "Availability.",
answer: "B. Flexibility.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following does not explain the poor development of inland waterways in Africa?",
A: "Insufficient goods to carry along the routes.",
B: "Presence of rapids and waterfalls.",
C: "Obstruction by floating vegetation.",
D: "High seasonality of the rivers.",
answer: "A. Insufficient goods to carry along the routes.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The area east of Cape Three Point in Ghana receives relatively low annual rainfall because  \nI. the sharp bend of the coast from a northwesterly to northeasterly alignment.’  \nII. The influence of the warm Guinea currents.  \nIII. The upwelling of the waters near the coast,  \nIV. The absence of a mountain barrier.",
A: "II and III only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "II, III and IV only",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The Executive Secretariat of ECO WAS is located in",
A: "Lagos.",
B: "Abuja.",
C: "Banjul.",
D: "Lome.",
answer: "B. Abuja.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]